ipromote.com 2008-05-08

# iPromote Web User Privacy Policy

This privacy policy discloses the privacy practices of iPromote.com. 

###  Does iPromote Collect Any Personally Identifiable Information From Web Surfers? 

No. All Web surfers who receive ads served by iPromote retain complete anonymity where iPromote is concerned. As ads are served, iPromote does not acquire or collect any personal information about you. Your name, address, phone number, and e-mail address all remain your private information. Like most standard Web servers, iPromote uses log files to collect data that is non-personally identifiable such as Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser types, referring/exit pages, operating system types, and date/time stamps. iPromote uses this data to categorize users by certain categories such as Windows users, Mac users, etc., which in the aggregate help us to determine which ads perform best and which content is most appropriate for different users on an anonymous basis. 

There are instances where a Web user may provide specific personal information in response to an ad containing a survey, purchase agreement, or registration questionnaire. For such programs, iPromote acquires this information on behalf of the Advertiser. The Advertiser uses this information to deliver the goods or services requested by the user. Any personal information that a user voluntarily provides to an Advertiser is subject to the privacy policy of that Advertiser. We recommend that anytime you choose to voluntarily submit personal information online, you should first visit and review the privacy policy of that site. 

###  Why Does iPromote Collect "Non-Personally Identifiable Data"? 

The anonymous information that we collect on behalf of our clients is useful only to the specific advertisers who employ us to deliver ads, and only in the context of our selection of ad-content and our reporting of ad-effectiveness to our client. In order to assess an ad campaign's effectiveness, we use cookies and pixel tags under our Internet domain iPromote.com, or in the client's domain to better define categories and determine which categories Web users belongs to. This means, for example, that of the millions of Web users we deliver banners to each month, an advertiser will know what percentage of those users viewed their ad with a certain browser. The sharing of this information is essential to providing the services we offer. iPromote may augment Web user information with additional non-personally identifiable information, such as an IP address to 5-digit postal code cross reference to aid in local targeting of advertising. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information by iPromote. 

###  What are Cookies? 

A cookie is a small amount of data that your Internet browser puts on your computer's hard drive. Cookies are not viruses and cannot erase your hard drive or harm your computer. Each cookie can only be read by the server that created that cookie, and provides no personally identifiable information about the individual using the computer. Cookies are used to sequence the delivery of a series of ads to your web browser, and to limit the number of times your web browser receives the same advertisement. They are also used by our reporting system to estimate the total reach of an ad campaign, the number of times an ad is clicked on, and how many Web surfers visit an Advertiser's site. 

The use of cookies has become industry standard for many, if not most, of the thousands of companies doing business on the Internet, and we believe that the use of such tools actually makes advertising on the Web less intrusive because users are not bombarded with repeat and irrelevant messages. Nevertheless, iPromote firmly believes that every individual who uses the Internet should be able to make informed decisions with respect to individual privacy matters, including the use of cookies. Thus, we are happy to provide you with a number of choices. You can choose to accept or refuse cookies by changing the settings in your Internet browser. You can also opt to be warned before a cookie is put on your computer. You can also choose to periodically delete cookies from your computer's hard drive, clearing out all historical data that may have been saved from your previous online sessions. In addition, iPromote provides you the opportunity to opt-out of just iPromote's cookies by following the opt-out procedure set forth below. 

###  How Can Users "Opt-Out" of iPromote Cookies? 

iPromote provides you the opportunity to "opt-out" of receiving iPromote cookies. Following the opt-out process, you will continue to have one iPromote cookie on your computer, but for all intents and purposes, it will contain only an "off switch" used merely to tell us not to put any new cookies on your computer. When we see this "off switch," we will know not to attempt to assign other cookies to you in the future and we will not collect any additional information from you. Since the opt-out cookie does not contain a unique user ID number, it does not allow us to identify your browser uniquely. If you desire to "opt-out" of iPromote cookies now, [click here](http://www.ipromote.com/opt-out/). There are also two additional options for Web surfers who wish to opt-out of receiving cookies. At any time, you can follow the simple procedures below to either manually delete cookies from your hard drive or automatically block the use of all cookies by changing a setting in your browser. 

###  How Can Users Delete Cookies? 

One way you can delete cookies stored on your computer, and therefore interrupt the process by which Web sites and advertisers collect non-personally identifiable information, is to delete all cookies on your computer's hard drive. This will delete cookies from our clients and everybody else. Depending on your Internet browser, you can delete all cookies in the following way: 

Microsoft Internet Explorer 6.x 

  * Menu: Tools-Internet Options 
  * Select Tab: Settings 
  * Select Tab: View Files 
  * Select and delete the cookies you want to delete from your hard drive. 

Navigator 4.x 

  * Menu: Edit-Preferences 
  * Select Category: Advanced 
  * Find section: Cookies 
  * Select your choice 

Please consult the user manual or help file for your particular browser for any changes to the above process. 

###  How Can Users Block Cookies? 

One way you can stop cookies from being put on your computer is to block all cookies by disabling cookies in your Internet browser configuration. This will block cookies from our clients and everybody else. Depending on your Internet browser, you can block all cookies in the following way: 

Microsoft Internet Explorer 6.x 

  * Menu: Tools-Internet Options 
  * Select Tab: Privacy 
  * Pull "slider" to "Block All Cookies," which is the highest setting 

Netscape Navigator 4.x 

  * Menu: Edit-Preferences 
  * Select Category: Advanced 
  * Find section: Cookies 
  * Select your choice 

###  What are Action Tags? 

Action tags (also known as clear gif technology) are tiny transparent graphic image files placed in a Web site, which are served by iPromote and counted when served. iPromote uses these action tags to track the completion of transactions and submittal of applications. In essence, action tags tell us that an event or "action" has occurred, for instance that something was clicked on, submitted, or purchased, but it conveys no real details about that event, nor does it provide any personally identifiable information about the user that initiated it. We use cookies and action tags primarily to: (i) report to iPromote's advertiser and Web site clients the estimated total reach of an ad campaign; (ii) report the frequency with which an ad was shown to a user and other measurement statistics; (iii) ensure that an ad displayed to a user corresponds to the correct click-through destination; (iv) deliver a series of advertisements in the proper sequence; and (v) limit the number of times a browser is delivered the same advertisement. If you prefer not to see iPromote-served advertising banners when you browse Web pages we can install a cookie on your computer that will block any advertising banner we serve and instead show just a blank area where that ad banner would have been. If you desire to "opt-out" of iPromote ad banners, [click here](http://www.ipromote.com/opt-out/). 

###  What is the Platform for Privacy Preferences ("P3P")? 

The Platform for Privacy Preferences (P3P) provides a way for Ad Networks and Web sites to publish their privacy policies in a machine-readable syntax. An Ad Network or Web site will deploy P3P in order to make its privacy practices more accessible to the site's visitors. A visitor's Web browser can download the machine-readable privacy statements, and compare the contents of those statements to the user's preferences. This way, the user's browser can automatically notify the user when they visit a site whose practices match the user's preferences – or warn the user if the practices and preferences don't match. iPromote has incorporated this technology into their ad servers in order to make its privacy practices more accessible to users. 

###  Linked Sites 

When you leave this site though links found on this site to other websites (whether knowingly or not) iPromote can no longer be responsible in any way for any material that you encounter and iPromote excludes (to the fullest extent permitted by law) any liability that may arise with respect to or as a result of such material causing any damage, costs, injury or financial loss of any kind. Please be aware that linked sites are not covered by this privacy policy although they may adhere to their own similar policies. iPromote does not assume any responsibility or liability for the actions, products, services and content of linked sites. We recommend that you visit and review the privacy policies of linked sites, as we have no control over information that is submitted to, or collected by, these third parties. 

###  Contacting iPromote 

iPromote openly volunteers its privacy practices. If you have any questions or you feel we are violating any privacy principle, please contact us at [privacy@ipromote.com](mailto:privacy@ipromote.com). If you do not receive acknowledgment of your inquiry or if you think that your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, then you may contact BBBOnline at http://www.bbbonline.org/consumer/complaint, a non-profit organization that assists customers with the resolution of such concerns. If BBBOnline finds us to be in violation of any privacy principle, we will correct the situation and stop processing the data of the user bringing the complaint. 

###  Changing Our Privacy Practices 

Please note that because of the changing nature of privacy laws, consumer needs, and our business, iPromote is committed to the constant monitoring and examination of its privacy practices, and may, from time to time, institute changes to its Privacy Policy. In the event that any material changes are made to the company's privacy practices, we will promptly make changes to this privacy policy and we will post these changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect and how we use it. Regardless of any future changes, however, we will never use the information you submit under this current policy in a new way without first providing you an opportunity to opt-out or otherwise prevent that use. 

###  Children's Privacy and Spam 

As of April 21, 2000 the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act became effective. The regulations apply to the online collection of personal information from children under the age of 13. iPromote is very sensitive to the issue of children's privacy and makes every effort to protect the privacy of children using the Internet. iPromote's Web site, products, and services are not developed for or directed at children. Our policy is not to permit anyone under the age of 18 to do business with us. If you believe your child has provided iPromote with any personally identifiable data by registering at iPromote's Web site, please e-mail us at [privacy@ipromote.com](mailto:privacy@ipromote.com) to have the data removed. We also request that all Web sites using our advertising network disclose in their privacy statements any and all information regarding the collection of information from children. In addition to the above, iPromote is committed to proper Internet practices and full compliance with the CAN-SPAM Act of 2003 (15 U.S.C. § 7701). It is our policy to prohibit the sending of unsolicited or "Spam" e-mail by iPromote or any of its marketing partners. 

###  A Special Note About the European Union 

European Union Web surfers understand and consent to the processing of personal information in the United States. 

###  iPromote Clients 

If you are a "client" of iPromote (i.e. an Advertiser or Web Publisher who has registered with iPromote to do business with iPromote) you are requested to provide personal information in order to participate in these programs. The collection of this information is part of regular business practices and is necessary in order to complete transactions and properly run and administer these services. Should anyone be uncomfortable providing this information to iPromote, they can choose not to participate. Information collected during the registration or application processes, include: company name, name, e-mail, street address, and phone number. Overall, Advertiser and Publisher information is used for administering the program, maintaining account information, and processing billing and payments. 

###  Security 

iPromote takes appropriate precautions to protect our users' information. Your account information is located on a secured server behind a firewall. When you enter sensitive information (such as credit card number or your password), we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). (To learn more about SSL, go to http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Secure_Sockets_Layer). iPromote also has an internal security policy with respect to the confidentiality of customer and other data, limiting access only to those employees who we reasonably believe need to know such information for the purpose of performing their jobs. Please keep in mind, however, that the Internet is not a 100% secure medium. Therefore, although we use reasonable efforts to protect information, the possibility of somebody defeating our security measures does exist. 

Though we make every effort to preserve user privacy, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law wherein we have a good faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with an appropriate law enforcement investigation, current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on our ad servers or Web site. In addition to the above, there is also the possibility that iPromote, or part of the company, may one day be purchased by, or merged with, another company. If that's the case, the acquiring (or merging) company will have access to our information.
